"This Land is Your Land, This Land is My Land, From California to the
New York Island. This land was made for you and me."
Bound for Glory is a music, drama film directed by Hal Ashby.
A biography of Woody Guthrie, one of America's greatest folk singers.
He left his dust-devastated Texas home in the 1930s to find work,
discovering the suffering and strength of America's working class.
Woody Guthrie, played by David Carradine.
Ozark Bule, played by Ronny Cox.
Mary / Memphis Sue, played by Melinda Dillon.
Pauline, played by Gail Strickland.
Locke, played by John Lehne.
Slim Snedeger, played by Ji-Tu Cumbuka.
Bound for Glory is a 1976 American biographical film directed by Hal Ashby, produced by folk music impresario and Woody Guthrie's manager
Harold Leventhal and loosely adapted by Robert Getchell from Guthrie's 1943 partly fictionalized autobiography Bound for Glory.
The film stars David Carradine as folk singer Woody Guthrie, with Ronny Cox, Melinda
Dillon, Gail Strickland, John Lehne, Ji-Tu Cumbuka and Randy Quaid.
Much of the film is based on Guthrie's attempt to humanize the desperate Okie
Dust Bowl refugees in California during the Great Depression.
Bound for Glory was the first motion picture in which inventor/operator
Garrett Brown used his new Steadicam for filming moving scenes.
Director of photography Haskell Wexler won the Academy Award for
Best Cinematography at the 49th Academy Awards.
All of the main events and characters, except for Guthrie and
his first wife, Mary, are entirely fictional.
The film ends with Guthrie singing his most famous song, "God Blessed America for Me" (subsequently retitled "This Land Is Your Land"), on
his way to New York, but, in fact, the song was composed in New York in 1940 and forgotten by him until five years later.
The film explores themes of biography, great depression, folk music,
based on memoir or autobiography, riding the rail.
The tone is emotional.